Kurt Statham

Veteran of the casual games industry in search of a new challenge

Los Angeles, CA (415) 321-0979 larvakurt@gmail.com

EXPERIENCE

DEFY Media — Director, Site Production

APRIL 2017 - OCTOBER 2018

- $\boldsymbol{\cdot}$ Manage all scheduling and production for the Addicting Games and Shockwave websites
- Review and approve all prospective Shockwave site content
- Serve as the technical liaison between the site production and engineering teams
- Maintain relationships with a variety of content partners
- Troubleshoot and remedy any production-related site issues
- Supervise and train junior staff
- · Assist in transitioning sites to new ownership

Nickelodeon/DEFY Media — *Game Release Engineer*

JULY 2011 - MARCH 2017

- Produce and QA casual online and downloadable games
- · Wrap download games in DRM software and deploy to site
- · Modify download game installers to offer various toolbars
- · Coordinate content delivery for several dozen daily games
- Write scripts to automate various file creation and text processing tasks

Nickelodeon — Games Tester

JUNE 2008 - JUNE 2011

- Identify and isolate game and site issues
- Verification of bug fixes/regression testing
- Ensure a consistent user experience across all titles

Nickelodeon — Assistant Manager, Customer Support

MARCH 2007 - MAY 2008

- Organize and supervise team projects
- · Assist customers with technical issues and billing inquiries

EDUCATION

City College of San Francisco — *Java Programming Certificate*

DECEMBER 2007

University of California, Berkeley — B.A., French

DECEMBER 2003

ABOUT ME

Over twelve years in the casual games industry

Strong background in casual game and website production

Experienced multitasker

Fast learner with a desire to apply new skills and concepts

Excellent written and verbal communication skills

Easygoing and naturally inquisitive, with a penchant for problem solving

SOME TECH I'VE USED

Python, MySQL, HTML, CSS, Windows, Mac, Linux, Git, SVN, Jira

NON-JOB STUFF THAT I DO

Ballroom Dance

Mostly Smooth, some Rhythm and Nightclub dances

Fostering Shelter AnimalsMostly cats, socializing them to make them more adoptable

Hiking

Mostly the higher peaks in the Angeles National Forest

Bass Player Mostly retired

LANGUAGES

English, French